Ms. Shalini Thulasidharan

D4, Sri Sai Avenue, Murugan Foundations, Mobile: +91-8610977178

Vengambakkam Road, Mappedu +91-9840954458

Chennai – 600 126 Email shalinithulasidharan@gmail.com

MOTIVATION

I am a self-motivated professional with flair to combine my creative ability and to utilize my exuberance to grow professionally and contribute to the growth of the group and organisation. I feel that my analytical background, personality and experience make me a strong candidate for this kind of role.

EDUCATION

Doctorate in Philosophy

Thesis Submitted

Crystal Growth Centre, Anna University, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

Thesis Title: Investigations on the growth and characterization of NdFeO₃ single crystals and

rare-earth doped ferrite nanoparticles.

Master of Science, Materials Science, Overall GPA: 8.2/10 2013

College of Engineering Guindy, Anna University, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

Thesis Title: *Synthesis and characterization of* Dy_2O_3 *electrospun fibers.*

Bachelor of Science, (Hons) Physics, Overall GPA: 7.9/10 2011

University of Madras, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow, Crystal Growth Centre, Anna University, Chennai, India; June 2015 - till date.

Job Profile: Responsible for performing research experiments, characterizing the samples and analyzing the data to be presented at various conferences.

Associated Research Analyst in Patent coding and drafting (Engineering Division), Thomas Reuters, Chennai, India; 2013 – 2014.

Job Profile: Responsible for coding of materials science related international patents for quality check.

Instrumental Experience: Have hands on experience on

Growth Equipment

Liquid / Vapor Phase Epitaxy System,
Spin Coating System

Four Mirror Optical Floating Zone Furnace,
High Temperature Box Furnace

Thermal Evaporator,
Chemical Vapor Deposition System

Characterization Equipment

XRD : PANalytical - X'Pert
UV Spectrophotometer

Analytical Softwares

Raman Spectroscopic analysis: Spec Win;
FTIR analysis: IR Pal 2.0
Spectragraph,

➤ UV-Vis Analysis : Spectra Manager

> XRD : Fullprof Retvield Refinement

PAPERS PUBLISHED

➤ **Title**: Studies on structural and magnetic properties of NdFeO₃ single crystals grown by optical floating zone technique.

Journal : Bulletin Materials Science **DOI No :** 10.1007/s12034-020-02259-4

Title: Investigations on the structural and magnetic properties of $Nd_{1-x}Gd_xFeO_3$.

Journal : Bulletin Materials Science **DOI No :** 10.1007/s12034-021-02399-1

SEMINARS

Short term courses: Global Initiative of Academic Networks (GIAN), Crystal Growth Centre, Anna University, Chennai; 12th – 20th February 2018; 12th – 16th September 2017; 06th – 12th January 2017;

Poster Presentation "Effect of sintering temperature on the physical properties of perovskite PZN-PT"-National Conference on Materials Science & Technology, Thiruvanandhapuram, Kerala, India, during 12-14th July 2017.

Two Day Workshop on AFM, MFM, EFM, KPFM, STM & PFM (Lecture cum Demonstration Programme), Crystal Growth Centre, Anna University, Chennai, India. 10th – 11th August 2017,

ACADEMIC ACHIVEMENTS

- ✓ University rank holder in Bachelors (Physics) from University of Madras.
- ✓ Received proficiency awards in the examination conducted by University of Madras for the year 2009-2010 & 2010-2011.

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

Soft Skills: Have developed excellent communication skills during the course of my studies and work as an analyst.

Language Skills

Tamil / English: Native Speaker